Taral Shah

Data Analyst | TeleMedicine Engineer | Biomedical Engineer

L 289 380 7672 (Toronto, Ontario)

in taral-shah-87215163

xtaral81291@gmail.com

https://data81291.github.io/

TeleMedicine Engineer with 3 years of hands-on experience dealing with **Data Analysis and Healthcare devices**.

Microsoft Professional Certificate in Data Science and support on various cardiology and radiology products.

Experience with **Business Analytics** using Power BI, Tableau, and Various Python libraries.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow

SharpestMinds, Toronto, ON, Jan 2020 - Present

- Extract and manipulate data from various sources to create a data pipeline.
- Identifies and understands new and emerging patterns through various data analysis techniques.
- Building a full-stack machine learning web application using Python(Scikit-learn, TensorFlow) and Azure Machine Learning Studio.

Telemedicine Lead Engineer

CompuMed Inc., Toronto, CA, Jan 2018 - Present

- Install and Maintain ECG Servers and databases from different vendors like GE, Schiller, and Mortara.
- Building a data pipeline that uses 5 ECG Servers and 3 PACS databases to a centralized database with 40+ features.
- Processed large volumes of granular healthcare data and conducted a statistical analysis to determine the robustness of interpretation.
- Built an automated study upload insight reporting tool (C#, Python) to assess the strengths & weaknesses of the client's user experiences. Reduced upload time by 65% which lead to new product offerings with reduced turnaround time.
- Utilized data visualization techniques and created dashboards (Python, Power BI) for insight into cardiology and radiology study volume, revenue and KPIs.
- Translated statistical findings to various levels of management and played a key role in purchase and software development decisions.

Biomedical Engineer

CompuMed Inc., Los Angeles, USA, May 2014 – Jan 2018

- Primary technical point of contact for Diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve different types of medical equipment and PACS/RIS platforms.
- Playing a key role in the development of improved processing workflows for decreased operating costs.
- Evaluate and support the roll-out of new technology.
- Design and integration of EHR Platform and related data flows.

□ SKILLS

LanguageSoftwarePythonPower BISQLAzure MLMATLABTableauRSharePointC SharpDBeaver & SSMS

Techniques & Tools

Python (Pandas, statsmodels, Selenium)
Visualization (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly)
Machine learning (Scikit-Learn, PyTorch)
GitHub (Project Management)
Experimental Design (AB Testing)
Business Analytics

R PROJECTS

Technical Support improvement using python and zendesk for the development of automated support.

ML model to improve turn-around time of ECG and ECHO using various python libraries and Azure ML

Data **Visualization Library** for healthcare diseases based on **Project TYCHO**.

Developing **Dashboard** using Power BI for KPIs.

EDUCATION

Microsoft Professional Certificate in Data Science

Microsoft Online, edX, 2017

MS in Biomedical Engineering

Wayne State University, Michigan, USA, 2014

BTE in Biomedical & Instrumentation Engineering

Ganpat University, Gujarat, India, 2011